Let's look at what we have covered in the lesson so far.
لننظر فيما تناولناه في هذا الدرس حتى الآن.
We started off by introducing the project scope and pricing framework,
بدأنا بتقديم نطاق المشروع وإطار تسعيره ثم تكلمنا عن كيف أن هذان الشيئان مرتبطان
then we talked about how these two are interrelated.
بعد ذلك تكلمنا قليلًا عن استراتيجية وضع الأجر في بداية مشوارك المهني الحر.
Then we talked a bit about the rate strategy when you're starting a freelancing career,
وكيف يمكن أن يكون تحقيق أقصى قيمة للعميل شيئًا في صالحك
and how maximizing the value for the client can work in your favor.
وكيف يمكن أن يعمل تعظيم القيمة للعميل لصالحك.
Then we touched upon the NDAs,
ثم نظرنا سريعًا في الاتفاقات المهنية
which are non-disclosure agreements and service agreements,
وهي اتفاق السرية واتفاق الخدمة
and how to avoid the usual pitfalls.
وكيف نتجنب السقطات المعتادة.
Lastly, we covered the edge case of bypassing
وأخيرًا، تناولنا حالة متطرفة من تجاوز
the platform to help you traverse scenarios that you may not be expecting.
المنصة لمساعدتك على اجتياز السيناريوهات التي لا تتوقعها.
In the next lesson,
في الدرس التالي،
we'll talk about how to effectively manage your projects so that you can
سوف نتحدث عن الكيفية التي يمكن أن تدير بها مشاريعك بكفاءة حتى
maximize the value for the client as well as balance it with a good revenue for you.
تحقق أقصى قيمة للعميل وفي نقس الوقت تحقق عائد جيد لك.